얘들아, 짐 다 쌌어
준비 완료야
Hey! I'm all packed and ready to go.
아가야, 아빠랑 조이 삼촌은
오늘 여행 간단다
That's right. Daddy and Uncle Joey
are going on a trip today.
바베이도스에서 학회가 있거든
그치? '바베이도스' 해봐
We're going to a conference in Barbados.
Right? Can you say, "Barbados"?
바베이도스!
Barbados.
내겐 중요한 학회니까
Okay. I've gotta say, it means so much
to me that you guys are coming..
모두와서 연설좀 들어줘
all the way over there
to hear me give my speech.
아참, 내가 연줄 좀 동원해서
And I have a surprise.
I had to pull some strings..
너희 줄 패스도 구해놨어!
but I was able to get everyone passes
to the entire conference. That's right!
이거면 너희들도 고생물학회의
세미나에 전부 참가할수 있어!
These babies will get you into all
the paleontology lectures and seminars.
불참할수 있는 패스는 없니?
Do you have anything
that will get us out of them?
네 연설을 듣게 돼서 기쁜데
다른 시간엔
We're excited to hear the speech,
but the rest of the time..
물놀이해도 되겠지?
we're gonna want to do island stuff.
데이빗도 강연 듣고 싶을거야
David will probably want to hear
a few lectures.
- 맞아, 과학자니까!
- 그게 아니라
- Right, because he's a scientist.
- No, no.
8년동안 민스크에만 있었기
때문에 직사광선에 노출되면
He's been in Minsk for eight years.
If he gets too much direct sunlight..
사망할지 몰라
he'll die.
우린 출발하자
- Okay, we'd better go.
- Yeah?
- 얘들아, 내일봐!
- 그래, 어서가자
- So we'll see you guys tomorrow.
- All right, let's do it.
찰리와의 5시간 비행이라!
음료수도 나눠 마시고
A five-hour flight with Charlie,
have a couple drinks..
담요도 함께 뒤집어 쓰면?
get under that blanket
and do what comes natural.
조이, 기내 담요는
투명망토가 아냐
It's a blanket, Joe,
not a cloak of invisibility.
프렌즈 시즌 9
'바베이도스에서 생긴 일 (1, 2부)'
- 정말 좋네요!
- 고생물학자들은 어떻고요!
- Wow, this place is beautiful!
- Look at all these paleontologists!
내일 수영장에 나가보면
핏기 없는 인간으로 가득하겠군
I know. There are gonna be some
pasty folks by the pool tomorrow.
- 세상에, 드디어 오셨군요!
- 또 스타를 알아보네
- My God, I can't believe you're here!
- I think I've been recognized.
- 늘 이렇다니까
- 겔러 박사님, 팬이에요
- This happens all the time.
- Dr. Geller? I am such a huge fan.
이건 꿈일거야
That never happens.
수년간 박사님 업적을 연구했죠
빨리 기조연설을 듣고 싶어요
I've been following your career for years.
I can't wait for your keynote speech.
- 기분 좋은데요
- 사인좀 해주세요
- Wow! This is very flattering.
- I would love your autograph.
그러죠
Well, sure.
- 성함이?
- 새라
- "Dear..?"
- Sarah.
"새라, 당신을 캐내고 싶어요"
"Sarah. I dig you."
- "로스 겔러 박사"
- 감사합니다
- "Dr. Ross Geller."
- Oh, thank you so much.
뭘요, 인사하세요
동료인 찰리 윌러 박사
Sure. Sarah, I'd like you to introduce you
to my colleague, Professor Wheeler.
- 여긴 조이 트리비아니
- 고생물학자세요?
- And this is Joey Tribbiani.
- Are you a paleontologist?
아뇨, 그럴리가요
전 배우죠
No, God, no, no.
I'm an actor.
우리 인생의 그날들
보셨어요?
You probably recognize me from a
little show called The Days of Our Lives.
우리 인생의 나날들이잖아
'그'자는 없었다구
Dude, it's just Days of Our Lives.
There's no "the."
그래, 로스! 맞아
드레이크 박사로 출연했죠
Okay, Ross. Boy, you.. Yeah.
No, no. I play Dr. Drake Ramoray.
- 죄송한데 전 TV가 없어요
- TV가 없어요?
- I'm sorry. I don't own a TV.
- You don't own a TV?
그럼 가구배치는 어떻게 하죠?
What's all your furniture pointed at?
- 어쨌거나, 만나서 반가웠어요
- 저도요
- Well, it was a pleasure to meet you all.
- You too, Sarah.
세상에, TV가 없다니
Jeez, who doesn't own a TV?
사실, 나도 없어요
Well, actually, I don't.
그래, 내것도 두달전에
망가져서 아직 안샀어
Yeah, and mine broke two months ago
and I still haven't gotten a new one.
두사람한테 딱 맞는
학회에 오셨구먼
Well, didn't you two come
to the right convention.
데이빗
David, can you help me?
챈들러에게 비행기가
뜨는 원리좀 설명해줄래요?
I'm trying to explain to Chandler
how a plane stays in the air.
그건 '베르누이 원리'와
Certainly. That's a combination
of Bernoulli's Principle..
- '뉴턴 운동법칙'의 조화예요
- 거봐!
- and Newton's third law of motion.
- See?
"바람하고 상관 있다"랑
어차피 같은 뜻이야
Yeah. That's the same as,
"It has something to do with wind."
가서 여행용품 좀 사올게
I'm gonna go pick up a few things
for the trip.
나도 같이가
내일 같이 택시 타고갈까?
I should go too. Now, tomorrow do you
want to share a cab to the airport..
아님 마이크랑 나를
공항에서 만날래?
or should Mike and I meet you?
마이크가 대체 누구람?
Mike? Who's Mike?
- 피비랑 헤어진 남자친구요
- 맞다!
- Mike's your ex-boyfriend.
- That's right!
완전히 까먹고 있었는데
Oh, yeah.
Wow, I had totally forgotten about him.
- 옛날생각 나네!
- 괜찮아요, 솔직해서 그런 거니까
- That's a blast from the past, huh?
- No, it's okay. Honest mistake.
아무뜻 없었어요
It really doesn't mean anything.
I mean, you know..
모니카가 언제나 챈들러를
'리처드'라고 착각하는 것처럼
Monica refers to Chandler
as Richard all the time.
- 그래?
- 일단 나가자
- She does?
- Let's get you out of here.
물귀신 작전 고맙다
Well, at least you took me down
with you.
미안, 마이크 생각이
떠나질 않아
I'm so sorry. I just..
I keep thinking about Mike.
데이빗이 좋고
함께 있으면 행복한데
I'm crazy about David, and
we're having so much fun together.
왜 마이크가 그리울까?
곧 잊게 되겠지?
Why? Why do I miss Mike? That's just..
That's gonna go away, right?
- 그럴거야, 조만간
- 그래
- Well, I guess. In time.
- Yeah.
난 리처드 완전히 잊었거든
I mean, my feelings for Richard
are certainly gone.
또 시작일세, 챈들러에 대한
사랑이 완전히 식었어
You just did it again. Chandler. Your
feelings for Chandler are certainly gone.
피비가 마이크에 대한
미련을 못버린것 같죠?
Boy, Phoebe's still pretty hung up
on that Mike, huh?
잘 모르겠던데요
I wouldn't read too much into it.
옛애인 이름으로 불리는게
Still, a girl calls you
by her ex-boyfriend's name..
- 유쾌한 일은 아니잖아요?
- 앞이 뻔하니
- that's not a good thing, right?
- Let me stop you there.
이쯤에서 관두죠
전 훌륭한 조언자가 못 되거든요
Because I think I see where this is going.
I'm not very good at giving advice.
로스나 모니카를 만나보세요
See, if you want advice,
go to Ross or Monica. Or Joey..
피자토핑이나 소변 볼때의
떨림은 조이한테 물으시고요
for advice about pizza toppings
or a burning sensation when you pee.
귀찮게 해서 미안한데
어떻게든 하고 싶어요
I'm sorry, I just wish there
was something I could do, you know?
- 아시다시피 피비가..
- 정말 후회 안하겠어요?
- Well, you know Phoebe..
- Seriously, we're gonna do this?
피비의 기억에서
마이크를 지우고 싶어요
I'm sorry, I just wish I could make her
forget about Mike already.
근데 둘은 왜 헤어졌죠?
- Why did Phoebe and Mike break up?
- Because his penis was too big.
그남자 바짓가랑이가
너무 두툼해서요
거봐요, 내가 이렇다니까
I'm sorry. That's the kind of thing I do.
마이크가 결혼을 기피해서
깨졌어요
They broke up because Mike
didn't want to get married.
본인이 결혼에 관대하단걸
암시해주면 어떨까요?
What if you let Phoebe know
you'd be open to marriage?
좋은 생각이에요
청혼하겠어요
That's great. That's great.
I'll propose to her.
네?
What?
어차피 언젠가는 할 참이었죠
I was probably going to do it
at some point.
- 당장하란 뜻은 아닌데
- 안될거 없죠
- No, I didn't mean now.
- Well, why not? It's brilliant.
"잘 살아요, 마이크
식장에서 봅시다!"
"Goodbye, Mike.
We'll see you at the wedding, fella.
"댁의 이름이
초대 명부에는 없겠지만!"
Well, we probably won't invite you
to the wedding, but.."
- 정말 고마워요, 챈들러
- 뭘요
- Well, thank you, Chandler. Sincerely.
- Well, you're welcome.
도움이 됐다니 기쁘네요
Glad I could help.
- 청혼은 어떻게 하면 좋을까요?
- 읽는척 하는거 안보여요?
- How do you think I should propose?
- I'm pretending to read here.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
반가워요
Yeah. How you doing?
Hey, how are you?
끈 수영복 입는다면서요?
You said you were gonna wear a thong.
Where's the thong?
끈 수영복이 아니라
끈 샌들이라고 했죠
I didn't mean a thong.
I meant thongs.
그런 문제는 분명하게 해줘요
You really should have been
more clear about that.
로비에서 누구 봤는지 알아?
You're never gonna guess
who I just saw downstairs.
브리트니 스피어스?
Britney Spears!
그래, 학회에 빠질수 없는
사람이지
Yeah.
She never misses these conferences.
- 케네스 슈워츠 박사를 봤어요
- 어머나!
- No, I just saw Dr. Kenneth Schwartz!
- Oh, my God!
얘기도 해봤어요?
- I know!
- Did you talk to him?
어떻게 감히 말을 걸어요?
Oh, yeah. What am I gonna say
to Kenneth Schwartz?
이러면 되지, "박사님!
브리트니 스피어스가 아니군요"
You could say, "Hey, Kenny,
how come you're not Britney Spears?"
- 갈까요?
- 벌써요?
- You ready to go?
- You're gonna go now?
- 놀다갈줄 알았는데
- 종일 세미나가 있고
- I thought we could hang out.
- I can't. I have seminars all day.
로스의 연설도 봐줘야 해요
I promised Ross
I'd look at his speech.
대신 발코니에서 저녁해요
낭만적일 거예요
But maybe we could have dinner later?
Out on the balcony? It'll be romantic.
끈 수영복 입고?
Will you wear a thong?
조이가 입으면 나도 입죠
I will if you will.
거래치고 묘하군요
You got yourself a very weird deal.
- 난 됐어, 저녁약속 있어
- 알았어
I'm good. I have dinner plans.
- 혼자 괜찮겠어요?
- 그럼요
- So you gonna be okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
할일이 산더미죠
해변도 가고 헤엄도 치고
I got tons of stuff I could do.
I'm gonna hit the beach, go swimming.
너 밖에 봤니?
Joe, have you looked outside?
아니, 왜?
No. Why?
- 젠장!
- 실내수영장에 가면
- Oh, man.
- There's an indoor pool.
되겠네요
- You could swim there.
- Yeah.
목적은 수영이 아니라
모래구덩이 파는 거라구요
I wasn't gonna swim.
I was gonna dig a hole.
'마이크'라고 불러서 황당했지?
That Mike thing was interesting.
I don't know what's gonna happen..
- 둘 사이가 어떻게 될까?
- 난 알아, 힌트 줄까?
- with Phoebe and David.
- I do. Want a hint, huh?
맹세합니다
I do.
맹세해요!
얼굴이 불그스레하고
Okay, I'm sensing this is
some kind of wordplay..
묘한 미소까지 띤걸 보니
말장난이 분명한데
because you are pink
with barely controlled glee.
- 데이빗이 피비한테 청혼한대
- 뭐야? 왜?
- David's gonna propose to Phoebe.
- What? Why?
마이크를 이길 방법을 얘기하다
Because we were talking about ways
he could beat Mike..
결혼 얘기가 나왔어
and I told him Phoebe wanted
to get married.
내가 말했잖아
Chandler, we have talked about this.
자긴 충고는 금물이라구
You are not supposed to give
people advice!
부적절한 농담이라도
할수는 없었어?
Couldn't you have made
some inappropriate joke?
했어
I did!
페니스에 대해서!
A penis one!
대체 내가 실수한게 뭐야?
Just so I know, what was so wrong
about what I said?
다시 만난지 얼마 안된데다
They've only been going out
for a few weeks.
피비는 마이크에
목매고 있잖아, 거절당하면
Phoebe is completely hung up on Mike.
I mean, she'll say no..
데이빗에겐 상처인데
둘 관계가 뭐가 되겠어?
David's heart will be broken,
it'll be too hard for them to recover..
결국 피비만 혼자가 되는거야
and then Phoebe will end up
alone again.
형편없는 충고를 했군
Man, that's some bad advice.
너희들 마침 잘왔다
Oh, hey.
Thank God. You guys are here.
- 왜? 무슨일 있어?
- 여긴 다 뒤죽박죽이야
- What's going on?
- Everything is upside-down here.
종일 비에 다들 TV도 안보고
로스까지 유명인사야!
It rains all day long and nobody
watches TV, and Ross is famous.
놀라지들마
I don't want to alarm anybody..
모니카 머리가 한 소쿠리야
but Monica's hair is twice as big
as it was when we landed.
파마머리는 습기에
Okay. When I go places
with high humidity..
부풀기 마련이야!
it gets a little extra body, okay?
신혼여행 사진속의
다이애나 로스가 그래서였군
That's why our honeymoon photos
look like me and Diana Ross.
가서 체크인하자
I'll show you guys where to check in.
자기야, 킹 사이즈 침대로!
Oh, honey? Can you make sure
we get a king-size bed?
데이빗, 우리도요
하트모양 있나 알아봐요
Oh, David, get one for us too. Oh, and
see if they have a heart-shaped one.
천장에 거울 있으면 더 좋고!
And with mirrors on the ceiling.
얘 옆방은 절대 안돼!
And make sure our room
isn't next to theirs.
너흰 짝이 있어서 좋겠다
Oh, you guys are so lucky
you're here with people.
나도 누구랑 방을 썼으면
I'd love to share this with someone.
너한텐 우리가 있잖아
우리가 널 사랑한다고
Oh, honey, you have us. We love you.
둘중 누가 나랑
잘거야?
Okay, which one of you
is gonna sleep with me?
이렇게 낭만적인 섬에서!
You know, it's just
such a romantic place.
나도 남자랑 방 썼으면!
I just wish I could share it with a guy.
- 조이는 포기해
- 조이?
- Not Joey.
- Not Joey. No.
- 난 챈들러가 탐났던 건데
- 어련할까
- I was just lusting after Chandler.
- Yeah, right.
오늘밤에 청혼할 겁니다
So.. I'm proposing to Phoebe tonight.
오늘밤에요?
Tonight?
약혼반지에는 보통
다이아몬드가 박혀있던데
Isn't an engagement ring
supposed to have a diamond?
보일듯 하네요
Oh, there it is.
업적없는 과학자는
벌이도 신통치 않거든요
Yes, well, being a failed scientist doesn't
pay quite as well as you might think.
70분의 1 캐럿이래요
That's one-seventieth of a carat.
투명도도 아주 낮고요
And the clarity is quite poor.
좋네요
Nice.
- 모니카, 얘기좀 할까?
- 알았어
- Monica, can I talk to you for a second?
- Okay.
데이빗이 오늘 청혼한대
David's gonna propose
to Phoebe tonight.
자기의 충고가 낳은
끔찍한 결과를 봤지?
See what happens
when you give people advice?
- 어서 말려봐
- 그것도 충고잖아!
- Well, I hope you told him not to.
- That would be advice!
알았어, 나한테 맡겨
Okay, fine. I'll handle this.
- 피비?
- 응?
- Phoebe?
- Yeah?
얘기좀 하자
- I need to talk to you.
- Are you leaving the Supremes?
다이애나 로스가
'슈프림스' 해체선언 하나?
챈들러가 데이빗에게
끔찍한 충고를 했어
Okay, my husband just gave
your boyfriend some very bad advice.
오늘밤 너한테 청혼할 거야
David's gonna propose to you tonight.
정말?
Wow, really?
신난다!
That's fantastic!
너 진심이야?
결혼하고 싶어?
What? Are you serious?
You want to marry him?
- 그럼 마이크는?
- 마이크랑 결혼시키려구?
- What about Mike?
- Oh, okay, you want me to marry Mike?
그럼 수갑에 재갈 채워서
Let's just gag him and handcuff him..
식장에 끌고와
and force him down the aisle, okay?
"피비를 아내로 맞겠습니까?"
I can just see it.
"Mike, do you take Phoebe?"
그래, 모든 여자들의 꿈이지
You know? It's every girl's dream.
그렇다고 엉뚱한 남자랑
결혼할 거야?
Do you really think marrying
someone else is the right answer?
중요한건 내가 마이크를
사랑한다는 거야, 아니, 데이빗!
Sure. Look, okay, bottom line?
I love Mike.. David!
난 데이빗을 사랑해
David! I love David.
그런 눈으로 보지마
다이애나 로스
Don't look at me that way,
Roseanne Roseannadanna.
CT촬영과
컴퓨터 이미지를 이용해
"By using CT scans and computer
imaging, we can, in a very real way..
중생대의 생생한 모습이
21세기에도 재현됩니다
bring the Mesozoic Era
into the 21st century."
굉장해요
It's great.
정말 그래요?
Yeah, you really think so?
학회의 히트작이 될거예요
You'll be the hit
of the conference.
내일은 훨씬 더 잘할거예요
It'll be even better tomorrow..
베개에 놓인 초콜릿을 찾으며
because I won't be constantly
interrupted by Joey..
훼방놓는 조이가 없을 테니까
checking to see if they put
chocolates on my pillow yet.
- 얘들아!
- 아직 초콜릿 안왔어
- Hey, guys.
- The chocolates aren't here.
젠장!
Damn it!
로스의 연설을 들었는데
굉장해요
Ross just read me his speech.
It's fantastic.
컴퓨터에 저장됐지?
읽어보고 싶은데
Oh, is it on the computer?
Because I'd love to give it a read.
이메일 읽고 싶으면
그냥 그렇다고 해
If you want to check your e-mail,
just ask.
뭐야?
그럼 볼게
What? May I?
웬 비가 이렇게 오니?
공룡주간에 신청할 때만 해도
What's with the rain, Geller? I mean,
when I signed up for dino week..
장마라는 말은 없었는데
nobody said anything
about it being monsoon season.
- 6월부터 12월까지 우기예요
- 누가 물었어요?
- The wet season is June to December.
- It's not the time, Charlie.
이런, 안돼!
Oh, no. No, no! Dear God, no!
경매에 나온
차주전자 놓쳤냐?
What, did someone outbid you
for the teapot?
마법 주전자?
Secret teapot.
컴퓨터 말야
다 날아갔어!
Your computer. I don't know what..
Everything's gone.
- 무슨 소리야?
- 바이러스가 분명해
- What do you mean?
- Must be a virus.
하드가 몽땅 지워졌어
I think it erased your hard drive.
맙소사!
무슨짓을 한거야?
What? Oh, my God. What did you do?
모르는 사람이 보낸
메일을 열었거든
Someone I don't know sent me an e-mail
and I opened it.
- 그런걸 왜 열어?
- 바이러스가 있단 말은 없었으니까
- Why? Why would you open it?
- Well, it didn't say, "This is a virus."
- 무슨 메일이었는데?
- "누드.."
- What did it say?
- "Nude.."
"테니스 선수
안나 쿠르니코바"
"Pictures of Anna Kournikova."
- 미안하다
- 그럼 내 연설은 어떡해
- I'm so sorry.
- What am I gonna do?
- 날아갔잖아
- 아니지
- My speech is gone!
- It's not gone.
사본이 있잖아
카피는 떠놨겠지?
I'm sure you printed out a copy.
You have a hard copy?
그런거 없어!
No, I don't!
그럼 지금 무지 열받았겠네
Well, you must be pretty mad
at yourself right now.
- 진짜 날아갔어?
- 응
- It's really gone?
- Yep.
다들 날씨나 불평하고
I'd like to thank you guys
for coming down here..
내 인생까지 망쳐줘서 고맙다
to complain about the rain
and ruin my career.
- 진짜 미안하다
- 그래야지!
- I just feel awful.
- Yeah, you should.
안나 쿠르니코바 누드? 메이저
대회에서 우승 한번 못한 선수잖아!
Nude pictures of Anna Kournikova? She's
never even won a major tournament.
빌리 진 킹이라고 하려다..
Well, I tried Billie Jean King, but..
잡아먹을 듯한 표정이
모니카랑 어쩜 그리 똑같냐
You know, you and Monica have
the same I'm-gonna-kill-you look.
모니카는 뽀뽀해주면 풀리던데
I can usually make it go away
by kissing her.
꺼져!
Get out.
나도 회사 컴퓨터가
자주 이러던데
You know, this happens all the time
to my computer at work.
- 그럼 어떻게 해결해?
- 다른 사람
- What do you do?
- I usually go..
컴퓨터로
테트리스 하면돼
play Tetris on somebody else's
computer.
어떻게 이럴수가 있어!
I can't believe this is happening.
내일이 기조연설인데!
I have to give the keynote speech
tomorrow.
사람들 앞에 서서
멍하니 있으란 말야?
I have to stand up in front of all
these people. What am I gonna say?
내가 외운 대사가 있는데
가르쳐줄까?
You can use a speech I memorized
for auditions.
스타워즈에 나오는 독백이
퍽 도움도 되겠다
I don't think your monologue from
Star Wars is gonna help me right now.
로스의 연설을 들어봤으니
Ross, we can solve this.
I just heard your speech.
- 밤새서라도 다시 써봐요
- 그게 가능할까요?
- We can re-create it. We've got all night.
- What, you really think we can do that?
아참, 조이랑 저녁약속 있지
Oh, wait. Joey and I
are supposed to have dinner.
괜찮아요, 로스나 도와줘요
Don't worry about that.
I mean, Ross needs you.
- 레이첼이랑 나도 도울게요
- 이런
Rachel and I will stay and help
any way we can.
좋아, 해보자
All right. Okay, let's do it.
탄소 연대측정의 단점으로
도입부를 시작한 다음
Well, I know we start by discussing
the shortcomings of carbon dating.
판게아 대륙의 분리로
And then I move on to what is clearly
the defining moment..
중생대를 구분했지
of the Mesozoic Era,
the breakup of Pangaea. Hello?
그리고..
트라이아스기로 넘어 갔어
And then there's the overview
of the Triassic.
'은하계 저 멀리!'는
없었냐?
Any chance any of this happened
in a galaxy far, far away?
- 여보세요?
- 마이크?
- Hello?
- Okay, Mike?
툭 터놓고 말하죠
피비랑 서로 사랑하는 감정은
Enough is enough.
You love Phoebe, and she loves you.
분명하잖아요
'결혼은 끔찍해' 타령은
So get over your
I-never-wanna-get-married thing..
당장 그만둬요
and step up!
누구세요?
Who is this?
피비 친구 모니카요
This is Monica, Phoebe's friend.
모니카군요, 다시 내 인생에
참견해 줘서 고마워요
Sure, Monica.
So good to have you back in my life.
피비가 데이빗을
다시 만나는데
Listen, Phoebe is back with David.
데이빗의 청혼에
승낙할것 같아요
He's gonna propose,
and she's gonna say yes..
하지만 피비가 원하는건
당신이라구요
but I know she really wants to be
with you.
청혼 한대요?
He's gonna propose?
뭐라고요? 머리 때문에
수화기가 귀에 안닿네!
I'm sorry, did you say something?
I can't hear through all this damned hair!
결혼문제는 피비한테 맡겨요
If Phoebe wants to marry David,
she should.
우리가 나설일이 아니잖아요
I'm not gonna stand in the way of that.
Neither should you.
명령은 당신이 아니라
내가 해요!
You don't tell me what to do.
I tell you what to do.
당장 바베이도스의
파라다이스 호텔로 전화해요
Just call her. She's at the Paradise Hotel
in Barbados.
댁도 곱슬머리니까 묻는건데
And while I've got you,
you've got curly hair.
습도가 높을땐 어떻게 하죠?
What do you do in the humidity?
끊어?
Damn it!
- 행복하시겠어?
- 나도 자기가 행복하길 바래
- Well, I hope you're happy.
- I hope you're happy too, honey.
피비가 결혼에 승낙하겠대!
Phoebe's going to say yes to David.
- 남의 인생에 참견 말랬잖아
- 승낙한다고? 잘됐네
- That's what happens when you meddle.
- Phoebe's gonna say yes? That's great.
아냐, 진짜로 사랑하는건
마이크라구
No, it's not.
She's still in love with Mike.
- 그럼 마이크랑 잘될순 없나?
- 전화해봤는데
- There's no chance that will work?
- No, I called.
- 가망없어
- 참견대장!
- It's not gonna happen.
- Meddler! Meddler!
자기가 참견 안했으면
If you hadn't meddled to start with..
나까지 안나서도 됐잖아
then I wouldn't have had to go in
and meddle myself.
이제와서 참견 안한다고
되돌릴수 없으니까
No matter how much we meddle,
we'll never be able to unmeddle..
하던 참견 계속 해야한다구
the thing that you meddled up
in the first place!
무슨 휴가가 이래!
This vacation sucks!
'고생물학자님들 환영합니다!'
따분해!
I'm so bored.
비 때문에
아무것도 못하구
Stupid rain. We can't do anything.
책 가져왔는데 읽을래?
Well, I brought some books.
We could read.
그정도로 따분하진 않다
Hey, it hasn't come to that yet.
먹어도 되죠?
Hey, hey, hey, don't mind if I do.
죄송합니다만
약사학회에 쓸겁니다
I'm sorry, sir, these are
for the pharmaceutical convention.
약사학회나 갈까?
You feel like going to a convention?
- 우린 약사가 아니잖아
- 누가 몰라?
- We can't. We're not pharmacists.
- I know we're not..
봐! 프랭크 마데이오
데바 추라로붐바.. 웜..
but Frank Madaio and Eva..
- 케이트 밀러
- 케이트 밀러, 좋네!
- Kate Miller.
- Kate Miller it is.
됐어!
- Okay.
- Oh, good..
이번주 내가 즐길
최고의 섹스로구나
And that's the most sex
I'm gonna have this weekend.
그럼 이왕 하는김에
확실하게 해주지
Well, in that case,
should I make sure it's on real good?
눈물나게 고맙다
Thank you.
케이트..
So, Kate..
요새 제약업계는 좀 어때요?
how's the pharmacy game treating you?
글쎄요, 프랭크
그리 순조롭지가 않네요
Well, Frank, I tell you, it's rough.
의사 선생님들의 글씨는
도무지 알아볼수가 있어야죠
I mean, is it me or is doctors' handwriting
getting harder and harder to read?
이해해요
I know, I know.
그렇지만
I tell you.
그대신 좋은점도 있잖아요
하얀 가운도 입고
But on the plus side,
we get to wear those white coats..
- 높은 판매대 뒤에 서있잖아요
- 그건 그래요
- and stand behind that really tall counter.
- Oh, that's true.
당신은 우리 인생의 나날들에
나오는 조이 트리비아니죠?
You're Joey Tribbiani
from Days of Our Lives.
이제야 누가 날 알아보는군!
Finally, someone recognizes me. Okay.
그런데요
우리 인생의 그날들이에요
And it's The Days of Our Lives.
- 재키, 그사람이야
- 맞아요, 재키, 이리 오세요
- Jackie, it is him.
- Yeah, Jackie, it's me. Come on over.
오, 세상에!
너무 흥분되네요
Oh, my God, this is so exciting!
여긴 무슨일로 오셨어요?
So why are you here?
새 영화에 약사역을 맡았거든요
연구하러 왔어요
I'm doing research for a role
in a new movie about pharmacists.
영화 제목은 사랑의 처방전이죠
Yeah, it's called Prescription for Love.
- 잘했어
- 고마워
- Nice.
- Yeah.
제친구 레이첼이에요
영화배우예요
This is my friend Rachel.
She's in the movie too.
전 영화배우예요
I'm an actress.
영화 내용이 뭐예요?
So, what's the movie about?
전 잘생기고 남성미 넘치는
약사로 나오고
Well, I play the handsome,
macho pharmacist..
레이첼은 제 학생이에요
and Rachel is my student..
제게서 제약업에 대한
who wants to learn all about..
모든걸 배우고 있죠
pharmacing.
맞아요, 제 캐릭터는
처음엔 소극적인데요
And, see, I'm shy at first..
나중엔 안경을 벗어 던지고
섹시하게 변해요
but then, I take off my glasses
and become sexy, you know.
노출 장면도 조금 있지만
굉장히 고상한 맛이 있어요
And there's some nudity,
but it's very tastefully done.
제 노출 장면은 절대로
고상하지 않아요
My nudity in the film
is not tasteful at all.
그럼, 약사에 대해서
연구를 하러 오셨다고요?
So you're doing research?
- 우리에게 질문하실건 없으세요?
- 물론 있죠
- Do you have any questions for us?
- I sure do.
저 커다란 핑크 음료는
어디서 구할수 있죠?
Where'd that guy get the big, pink drink?
그리고 다음에 한말이..
중생대에서 21세기로
Oh, and then you said that thing about
bringing the Mesozoic Era..
넘어오는 거였어요
into the 21st century.
그랬나요?
Well, yeah. That's it?
그게 다예요
그게 연설의 전부예요
That's it. That's the whole speech.
- 네
- 세상에, 우리가 해냈어요!
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God. We did it.
제가 한거겠죠
어쩜 그렇게 기억을 못해요
Actually, I did it, Ross. You remembered
shockingly little of your own speech.
대신 샴푸로
피라미드 쌓았잖아요
Yes, but I did make a pyramid
out of the bath products.
정말 굉장해요
얼마나 고마운지
Oh, this is amazing.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
목걸이 예쁘네요
That's a pretty necklace.
고마워요
Thank you.
자축의 의미로 샴페인 어때요?
Hey, what do you say we celebrate?
Champagne?
좋죠!
병에 물 채워서 마개 닫으면
Yeah! Save the cork, and that way,
we can fill the bottle with water..
호텔에서 청구 안할거예요
and put it back so they
don't charge you.
척척박사가 따로 없네!
Oh, my God, I love you.
엠마 참 귀여워요
얘는 아들이에요?
This is such a cute picture of Emma.
And is this your son..
아님 남의 아들 사진을
가져온 거예요?
or just some kid whose picture
you bring on vacation?
첫 결혼에서 얻은 아들
벤이에요
That's Ben, my son
from my first marriage.
- 첫 결혼?
- 네
- Your first marriage?
- Yeah.
결혼을 여러번 했어요?
You've been married more than once?
아뇨
No.
왜 헤어지셨어요?
So why'd you break up?
그러니까..
Oh, it was..
얘기가 좀 긴데
아내가..
It's complicated, you know?
She was..
레즈비언이었어요
gay.
그렇게 긴 얘기는
아니네요
Actually, it's not that complicated.
세상에!
Oh, my God.
이런일도 다 있네요!
This is so cool!
대놓고 그런 반응을
보일만도 하죠
Okay.
Odd thing to get excited about.
그게 아니라 제 약혼자도
알고 보니 게이였거든요
No, it's just that I was engaged
to a guy who turned out to be gay.
와! 박수 한번 쳐요!
Hey! High-five!
눈치 못챈 자신이
한심하지 않았어요?
Didn't you feel so stupid
that you didn't see the signs?
제 약혼자는 주말 내내
테니스 파트너랑 있었거든요
My fiance was always going on
long weekends with his "tennis partner."
벤 엄마도 365일
헬스클럽에 갔지만
My wife had a workout friend she went
to the gym with every day for a year.
뱃살은 그대로였어요
She didn't get any fitter.
나중에야 다들 말하죠
- Everybody's like, "I knew all along."
- I know.
- "난 알고 있었는데"
- 그러게요
알면 전화 주던지
메모라도 남길 것이지
If you knew, why didn't you tell me?
I mean, call, leave a note.
"지나는 길에 들렀어요
마누라 동성애자인건 알죠?"
"Hi. Just dropped by
to say your wife's gay."
- 그러게요
- 그럼
- I know.
- And then..
최악의 상황에서
최고의 수확을 거둘수 있죠
And then you try to make the best
of a bad situation..
예컨대 셋이 즐긴다거나
so you float the idea of a threesome.
난 그런적 없는데요
I didn't do that.
저도요!
Me neither.
약사들이 이렇게
재밌는지 몰랐네
Well, who knew? Pharmacists are fun.
그러게, 맨뒤 앉은 아줌마가
널 업고 갈 기세더라
I know. That old lady at the end
was ready to take you home.
약 드실때가 넘었나봐
Not enough pills in the world, Rach.
넌 어땠어
맘에드는 남자 없었어?
What about you, huh? You're the single
one. See anybody in there you like?
건장한 남자랑 얘기좀 했었지
Well, let's see. There was that
really big guy that I was talking to..
가슴이 아주 예쁘더라구
with the really nice breasts.
뉴욕에는?
거기에도 없어?
But what about back home? Anything
going on there? Anybody you like?
없어
No.
- 있구나, 얼굴 빨개졌네!
- 그게 아니라
- There is. You're blushing.
- No, I'm not blushing..
탄거야
and I'm sunburned.
비가 너무 많이와서
From, you know, the rain.
좋아하는 사람 있구나!
누구야?
You like someone. Tell me who.
- 누구냐니까?
- 정말없어
- Tell me who it is. Come on.
- No. Joey.
솔직히 말해
꼭 듣고 말거야
Who do you like?
You're not getting away that easy.
- 말해봐
- 조이!
- Who do you like?
- Joey, come on!
그만해, 어차피 소용없어
아무일도 없을 테니까
It doesn't matter, you know?
It's not like anything's gonna happen.
네 남자로 못 만들
이유가 어딨냐?
What? Why not?
Rach, who can you not get?
알았어
진짜로 알고싶어?
Okay. Okay.
You really want to know who it is?
- 응, 누구야?
- 진짜?
- Yeah. Who is it?
- Do you?
- 얘들아!
- 좀전에 메시지 남겼는데
- Oh, hey.
- I just left you a message.
로스랑 간식하려던 참인데
Ross and I were gonna go grab a bite..
조이가 왔으니
약속대로 나갈까요?
but now that you're here,
we could have that dinner.
그거좋죠
연설문은 끝냈어요?
Right! Of course.
Hey, did you guys finish the speech?
응, 다됐어
정말 고마워요
Yep! We got it. We got it.
Thank you so much.
- 저도 재밌었어요
- 그래요?
- I had a great time.
- Yeah.
얘기 끝났다고 생각하지마
누군지 꼭 알고 말테니..
This isn't over,
because I really want to know..
나중에
Later. Later.
- 갈까요?
- 네
- So shall we?
- Yeah.
- 먼저가요
- 잘가요
- Okay.
- Good night.
잘자
Good night.
- 잘자라
- 너도, 로스!
- Okay, good night.
- Good night, Ross.
데이빗의 청혼에 응하겠다니!
I can't believe she's gonna
say yes to David.
마이크를 좋아하면서 말야
She's clearly in love with Mike.
당신 헤어스타일 때문에
진지하기가 힘들어
You know, it's very hard to take you
seriously when you look like that.
샴페인 한병 주세요
Could we have a bottle
of champagne, please?
그리고 자금이 충분치 못하니깐
비싸지 않은 것으로 주세요
And I'm kind of on a budget,
so if you have anything local..
국산이나
캐나다산으로요
or Canadian.
피비, 저..
할말이 있어요
Phoebe, I have something I want to say.
청혼하려나봐
도저히 못보겠어, 가자
Oh, God, he's gonna do it.
I cannot watch this. Let's go.
아직 시간 많아
못들었어?
I think we have time.
Have you heard him talk?
"저.. 피비.. 영광스럽게.."
확 질러버려, 데이빗!
"Phoebe, I would be honored if.."
Spit it out, David!
저.. 피비..
Phoebe.
피비처럼 멋진 여자와
떨어져 있는건 고통이었죠
You're an amazing woman, and the time
we spent apart was unbearable.
민스크의 환경미화원이
파업했을 때보다 더!
Of course, the sanitation strikes
in Minsk didn't help.
그래서요?
Sure. Okay. Yeah.
다시 만나서 행복하고
절대 헤어지지 않겠어요
But, well, now that we're together
again, I don't ever want to be apart.
그러려면..
So to that end..
- 어머, 마이크!
- 난 데이빗이에요
- Oh, my God, Mike.
- It's David, actually.
아뇨, 마이크가 왔어요
No, Mike's here.
왔어요, 마이크?
Oh, hey, Mike.
안녕하세요, 데이빗
Hi, David.
챈들러!
모니카? 이런!
Chandler. Monic.. Oh!
습기 때문이라구요
It's the humidity!
- 반가워요, 피비
- 여긴 웬일이에요?
- Hi, Phoebe.
- What are you doing here?
물어볼게 있어서요
I have a question I need to ask you.
지금 내가 물어보려던 참인데
I have a question I was kind of
gonna ask her myself.
알아요, 근데 내가 먼저
물어봐야 해요
Yeah, I understand, but before you do,
she really needs to hear this.
알았어요
Okay.
- 아예 자리까지 내드릴까요?
- 그래주면 고맙죠
- Would you care for my seat as well?
- Actually, yeah, that'd be great.
좋아요, 장거리 비행에
지쳤을 테니
Well, that's fair, you've had a long trip.
사랑해요
Phoebe, I love you.
너무 보고싶었어요
I've missed you so much
these last few months.
당연한 이별이라 생각했는데
I thought we were apart
for a good reason..
평생 피비를 못본다는건
but I realized that there was
no reason good enough..
용납 못할 일이라 생각됐어요
to keep me from spending
the rest of my life with you.
내가 하려던 말이
나올차례 같은데
Kind of steps on the toes
of what I was going to say.
미안하지만 피비에게
꼭 할말이 있습니다
I'm sorry, David,
but she really has to know this.
얘기 끝나는 대로
밖에서 봅시다
All right, but after this,
I want to see you outside.
비가 그치거든
If it stops raining.
내가 만난 여자중에
최고의 여자예요
You're the most incredible woman
I've ever met.
이런 피비를 어떻게 놓치죠?
반지는 없지만..
How could I lose you?
Now, I don't actually have a ring.
나한테 있어요
- I have a ring.
- I wouldn't brag about that, big guy.
자랑할만한 반지는
아닌것 같은데요
피비..
But, Phoebe..
결혼해주겠어요?
will you marry me?
아뇨
No.
마이크를 사랑하지만
청혼을 바라진 않았어요
I love you, but I never needed
a proposal from you.
내가 알고 싶은건
I just needed to know
we were headed somewhere.
우리앞에 놓인 미래죠
- That we had a future.
- We can have any future you want.
피비가 원하는 미래를
만들어 가요
난 이만 가볼게요
Okay, well, I'm gonna take off.
데이빗, 미안해요
David, I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
혹시 내가 먼저 청혼했다면?
Just so I know, if I had asked first..?
승낙했겠지만
그건 잘못된 결혼이 되겠죠
Yeah, I might have said yes,
but that would've been wrong.
됐어요
Please, you don't have to explain.
민스크에 안갔으면
I mean, perhaps if I hadn't
gone to Minsk..
우리 사이가 잘 풀렸을텐데
경력에 오점을 남기지도 않고
things would have worked out for us,
and I wouldn't have ruined my career.
동상에 발가락을 잃지도 않고!
Or lost that toe to frostbite.
여행 즐거웠어요
It was a good trip.
- 안아도 될까요?
- 그럼요
- Is it okay if I hug you now?
- Oh, yes.
이게 다 우리 덕이에요!
Because of our meddling! All right?
조용하고 진짜 좋다
종일 누워있어도 되겠어
Oh, isn't this nice? It's so quiet.
I could just lie here all day.
그러게
Oh, I know.
커튼열어!
- Open your drapes! Open your drapes!
- So glad we got adjoining rooms.
방이 붙어있으면
이래서 좋다니까
- 해 떴다!
- 각막이 있단걸 잊고 지냈어!
- The sun is out!
- Hey! Remember when I had corneas?
- 가서 자리 예약해
- 알았어
Go to the pool and reserve chairs.
난 잡지랑 로션 챙길게
- I will get the magazines and the lotion.
- Ladies? Ross' speech is in 45 minutes.
아가씨들, 45분 후에
로스가 연설하는데요
- 젠장!
- 미치겠네
- No!
- Damn it!
얘들아, 방음이 안되거든
Walls are pretty thin, guys.
최근의 MRI와 DNA테스트를
분석해야 하는 이유는
"Then we have to weigh the data from
recent MRI scans and DNA testing..
단순한 탄소연대측정에서 오는
의문을 풀 정보를 찾기 위해서죠
which call into question information
gathered from years of carbon dating."
수영장에서 선탠하는
저 아줌마좀 봐
Look at the woman sitting out
by the pool getting tan.
구릿빛에 주름이 자글자글해
부러워라
She's all leathery and wrinkled.
I'm so jealous!
최근 다양한 종류의
공룡이 새로 발견됐는데
"Finally, factor in the profusion
of new species recently discovered.
기가노토사우르스
Giganotosaurus.
- 아르젠티노사우르스
- 썰렁 사우르스 시리즈군요
- Argentinosaurus."
- Not to mention Coldsaurus.
이건 초식동물입니다
육식동물은 말할것도 없죠
"And that's just the herbivores. I'm not
even gonna discuss the carnivores.
녀석들은 머리가 아주 크지만
Their heads are already too big.
오히려 뇌는 작습니다
Which is ironic, considering
their stunted cerebral development."
이게 웃겨요?
Really?
현재, 호모 에르가스테르는
"But all kidding aside,
in much the same way..
서서 직립한 호모에렉투스에서
파생되었다고 여겨지며..
that Homo ergaster is thought to be a
separate species from Homo erectus.."
- 왜요?
- 섰다잖아요
- What?
- He said "erectus."
- 장난해요?
- 로스가 그랬어요
- You're kidding, right?
- No, he really said it.
서서 직립한 원인은
"And while there are certainly
vast differences..
중생대 화석과 큰 차이가 있죠
between these Mesozoic fossils
and the example of Homo erectus.."
서?
Erectus?
- 호모!
- 그래 그것도 웃겨
- Homo.
- Right.
21세기에도 생생한 중생대를
볼수 있습니다
"In a very real way, we can bring
the Mesozoic Era into the 21st century."
감사합니다
Thank you.
- 잘했어요
- 훌륭해
- Really great.
- Oh, thanks, guys.
다들 고맙다
정말 대단했어요, 코넬대학의
자비스 오버블로입니다
I thought it was wonderful.
Jarvis Oberblau. Cornell.
이렇게 훌륭한 연구를
이토록 젊은분이..
I mean, the ideas you put forth,
and from someone so young and..
이손은 놓고 말할까요?
Okay, now we're just holding hands.
해변에 나갈까?
연설 참 좋았어
Alrighty. We're gonna hit the beach.
That was really great.
- 고마워
- 게다가 유머까지!
- Oh, thank you.
- Yeah. Oh, and so funny.
- 쉬어라
- 고맙다, 와줘서 정말 고마워
- Take it easy.
- All right, thanks. Thanks so much.
얼마나 힘이 됐는지 몰라
I can't tell you how much it means
that you were here.
절대 놓칠수 없는 학회죠
You kidding?
We wouldn't have missed it.
저 왔어요!
I'm back.
- 알았어, 실례할게
- 가봐
Okay. Well, excuse me?
- 어땠어요?
- 대단했어요
- Well?
- You were incredible.
다들 넋이 나갔던데요
You blew them away.
청중속의 찰리 얼굴도
정말 멋있었어요
I can't tell you how great it was
to look in the crowd and see your face.
찰리 입술이 날 따라
움직이던데요
I mean, did you know you were
mouthing the words along with me?
- 내가 언제요?
- 난 좋았어요
- I was not.
- No, it's okay.
록스타가 된 기분이던데요
It made me feel like a rock star.
그럼 난 열성팬이고요?
Oh, my God. I'm your groupie.
다 벗고 침대에서
날 기다리는건 아니겠죠?
Hey, I better not find you naked
in my hotel room.
제가 또 도를 넘었군요?
Look, I took it too far.
해변에 나간다며?
Hey, I thought you were
going to the beach.
- 또 비가 와
- 뭐?
- It's raining again.
- What?
정말이네
Would you look at that.
일주일 내내 비가 오다가
해가 뜬건
The only time the sun comes out
the whole weekend..
내가 연설을 하는
1시간뿐이었어
is the one hour I'm giving my speech.
저위에 누군가가
날 무지 좋아하나봐
Someone up there likes me.
이세상 사람들은
날 무지 미워하지만
But people down here are pissed.
비가 또 오네
이럴순 없어!
I can't believe it's raining again.
It's so unfair.
긍정적으로 생각해
Well, on the bright side,
now we won't have to see..
윗통벗은 고생물학자
안보니 다행이잖아
all these paleontologists
with their shirts off.
박사님들 말고요
Not you guys.
하던일 계속 하세요
You've got it going on.
- 오늘 뭐하지?
- 지하에 휴게실이 있대요
- What will we do today?
- They have a game room downstairs.
탁구대도 있을법 한데
They have Ping-Pong and stuff.
탁구?
자기야..
Ping-Pong?
Honey, they have Ping-Pong.
- 탁구치러 가자
- 안되겠는데
- Let's play.
- I don't think so.
- 왜?
- 당신 경쟁심을 누가 말려?
- Why not?
- You know how competitive you get.
귀엽다고 했지만
그건 거짓말이었어
And while I say it's cute,
others disagree, and I'm lying.
- 늘 심하게 굴진 않잖아
- 그래?
- I'm not always that bad.
- Oh, yeah?
지난번에 어땠지?
What happened when we played
last time?
자길 한대 갈겼지
I punched you.
- 또?
- 피비도
- And?
- Phoebe.
- 또?
- 너네 머리로 박치기했어
- And?
- I clunked your heads together.
- 여기 있었네요
- 왔어요?
- There you are.
- Hey. Listen.
비가 그치면
우리 스노클링 해요
As soon as it stops raining,
we have got to go snorkeling.
애들 말이 스노클 호흡기로
공기 방울을 불면
Some kid told me about this sea turtle.
If you blow bubbles in his face..
바다거북이 쫓아온대요
he chases you.
난 오후에 그룹회의가
있어서 안되는데
I'm sorry, I can't. I'm running
a discussion group all afternoon.
괜찮아요
놀사람 없으면 혼자하죠
That's okay.
I'll find someone else to do it.
근데 바다거북이
I'd do it alone, but..
찰리를 잡아가면 어쩌나?
I don't know what happens
if the sea turtle catches you.
미안해요
You know, I feel so bad.
어젯밤도 그렇고
내내 함께 못 있어줘서
I haven't seen you this whole trip.
Especially last night..
괜찮아요, 레이첼이랑
재밌게 잘 놀았어요
Don't worry about it. It was fine.
I had the best time with Rachel.
로스랑 방에 틀어박혀
연설 쓴 찰리가 안됐죠
I just felt bad for you, stuck
in that room working on Ross' speech.
아뇨, 오히려 재밌었어요
Actually, it turned out to be a lot of fun.
어쨌든 우리 둘다
잘지낸 셈이네요?
Oh, well, at least
we're both having fun, right?
근데 둘이 함께가
아니란건 이상하죠?
- Is it weird that it's not with each other?
- Yeah.
맞아요
조금은..
A little bit, yeah.
우리 얘기좀 해요
I think we need to talk.
그래야 할것 같네요
Yeah, I think we do.
근데 무슨 얘기를?
About what?
- 하자, 재밌을 거야!
- 알았어
- Come on, you guys, it'll be fun!
- All right.
- 대신 점수는 매기지 말자
- 그럼 승자는 어떻게 정해?
- I'll play if we don't keep score.
- Well, then how do we know who wins?
- 승패는 없어
- 그럼 패자만 넷이네?
- Nobody wins.
- So we're just four losers. Super.
- 난 모니카랑 안할래
- 나도!
- Well, I'm not playing with her.
- I'm out.
- 제가 상대하죠
- 좋아요!
- I'll play you.
- Okay.
이건 지옥으로
뛰어드는 짓이에요
- You don't know what you're doing.
- She gets crazy.
모니카는 장난 아니에요
상처 보이죠?
전자오락하다 맞은 거예요
This scar? That's from Pictionary.
괜찮아요
I think I'll be all right.
- 서브 넣을래요?
- 원하는 대로 해드리죠
- You want to volley a bit for serve?
- Sure, if you want to.
아참, 나 선수 뺨쳐요
Oh, by the way, I'm awesome.
세상에, 모니카 대 모니카다
Oh, dear God, there's two of them.
- 계속할래요?
- 그럼요
- You ready to play?
- Hell, yeah.
마이크가 이런
사람인지 알았니?
- Did you know this about him?
- No idea. I thought he was soft like you.
아니, 너처럼
약해 빠진줄 알았지
- 더 재밌게 할까요?
- 얼마 걸래요?
- Want to make it more interesting?
- How much you thinking?
- 게임당 10달러?
- 50으로 하죠
- Ten bucks a game?
- Make it 50.
- 백달러로 합시다
- 천달러..!
- I'll make it 100.
- One thousand..
그만!
Okay!
순서부터 정하죠
동전 있어요?
We'll flip to see who goes first.
You got a quarter?
너희 여자애들 동전 없니?
No. Either of you girls got a quarter?
그런 심한 말은
적한테나 해
Honey, try to focus the trash talk
on him.
- 모니카, 정해!
- 앞면! 아냐, 뒷면! 앞면 할게!
- Monica, you call it.
- Heads. No, tails! Heads!
- 뒷면이다
- 그냥 뒷면 할걸!
- Tails.
- Oh, what are the chances?
- 득점!
- 아니죠
- My point!
- Oh, no, I don't think so.
탁구 규칙에 따르면
라켓 안쥔 손이
Standard rules: If at any time a player
uses his nonracket-bearing hand..
테이블에 닿으면
득점은 무효가 되거든요
to touch the playing surface,
he or she forfeits the point.
전직 변호사거든
He was a lawyer.
동부지역은 화창하겠습니다
All the East Coast
is having beautiful weather.
뉴욕은 22도가 예상됩니다
In New York, it's 72 and sunny.
재수없는 기집애
Weather bitch.
열렸어
It's open.
- 조이?
- 저기..
- Hi, Joe.
- Hey.
- 얼굴이 왜그래?
- 찰리랑 헤어졌어
- What? Is everything okay?
- Charlie and I broke up.
왜?
No. Why?
우린 통하는게 없대
Well, she said
we have nothing in common.
말도 안돼
That's crazy.
아냐, 그건 그래
No, it's not.
We have nothing in common.
그렇긴해
- Yeah, that's true.
- Yeah.
찰리는 로스과잖아
I mean, she should be with someone
more like Ross.
입만 열면 어려운 말이구
You know, I mean he uses
all those big words too.
- 똑똑한 것들은 정말 따분해
- 야, 나는?
- Man, smart people are dull.
- Well, hey!
장난하지마
Okay, Rach.
너무 바보같지?
난 왜 엉뚱한 여자만 쫓지?
I feel so stupid, you know? Why do I
keep going after the wrong girls?
- 그게 무슨 소리야?
- 그렇잖아
- What are you talking about?
- Oh, come on.
너도 그렇고 찰리도..
난 왜 이렇게 생겨 먹었냐?
I mean, there's you, then there's Charlie.
It's like.. What the hell's my problem?
난 정말..
I just..
늘 엉뚱한 여자만
쫓는것도 아닐걸
Okay. Maybe you're not
always going after the wrong girl.
나한테 찰리는 안어울려
I'm telling you, Rach,
Charlie is not right for me.
- 찰리 말구
- 그럼 누구?
- I'm not talking about her.
- Well, then, who?
지난달에 사귄 웨이트리스?
The waitress I went out with last month?
- 됐어, 잊어버려
- 아냐
- You know what? Forget it.
- No, no, no, no.
- 대체 누구?
- 그게 있잖아
- Who are you talking about?
- No, I don't..
나도 누군지 모르겠어
I actually don't know who
I'm talking about, so..
알았어
- Okay.
- Yeah.
오늘밤에 묵을
방이나 알아봐야겠다
Well, I'm gonna go see
if I can get a room for tonight.
- 이따봐
- 그래
- And I'll see you later.
- Yeah, sure. Okay.
- 너, 나 좋아하니?
- 그게..
- You like me?
- Okay.
- 우리 괜히 호들갑 떨지말자
- 호들갑 떨만하지!
- Let's not make a big thing about this.
- It's a huge thing!
손발좀 맞춰보자, 조이
Okay, not working with me, Joe.
요즘들어 이 문제를
계속 생각해 봤거든
Look, here's the thing.
Lately, I have been having thoughts.
심사숙고란거 있잖아
Musings, if you will.
- 얼마나?
- 한달쯤
- Well, for how long?
- Oh, only like a month.
한달이나?
- A month?
- Well..
목소리좀 낮춰!
Dial it down. Listen, maybe they're
crazy thoughts, but sometimes I do.
정신나간 생각일지 모르겠지만
우리에 대해 생각하게 됐어
I have been thinking about,
you know, us.
- 소리 쬐금은 높여도 되거든
- 알았어
- Okay, dial it up a little.
- Oh, you're right. Okay.
- 물어볼게 있어
- 물어봐
- I just have a question.
- Shoot.
- 대체 이게 무슨 짓이니?
- 아무것도 아냐
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm not trying to do anything.
우리 함께한 시간이 좋았잖아
It's just, we have such a good time
when we're together, you know?
계속 그러면 어떨까
궁금하지 않니?
And I mean, aren't you just
a little curious what it would be like?
궁금? 궁금하고 말고
호기심 많은..
Am I curious?
I mean, I'm as curious as..
조지처럼
George!
- 누구?
- 원숭이 있잖아
- Who?
- Curious George!
노란 모자 쓰고
You know, the monkey and the guy
with the yellow hat.
- 그래, 기억난다
- 신문도 돌렸잖아
- Of course. I remember.
- He had a paper route.
그랬지
Yeah, he did.
- 내말이 바로 이거야
- 그래, 우린 잘 통했지
- See, this is what I'm talking about.
- No, I know. We're great!
하지만 레이첼
이럴순 없어
But, Rach, no, this can't happen.
가망없어? 이 만큼도?
Can't it just happen a little bit?
- 절대 불가능해
- 왜?
- No! It can't happen at all!
- Why not?
왜냐면!
솔직히 그러고 싶어
Because, look, no one wants
this to happen more than me, okay?
이순간에도 다시 시작하길
I have gone over this moment
in my head 100 times..
바라면서 갈등 때린다구
and not once did I ever say no.
근데 로스한테 못할 짓이야
I couldn't do it to Ross.
- 저번엔 상관없었잖아
- 그후에
- But that wasn't gonna stop you before.
- I know. I know..
곰곰이 생각했는데
그건 잘못한 일이었어
but I've thought about it a lot
since then, and it just wouldn't be right.
미안해
I'm sorry.
나도 미안
I'm sorry too.
- 괜한 말을 꺼냈나봐
- 아냐
- Oh, God, I shouldn't have said anything.
- No, no.
상관없어
No, no, no, no. Hey, we'll be fine.
- 네 말대로 호들갑 떨일 아냐
- 별일 아니라고?
- Like you said, it's no big deal.
- It's not a big deal.
- 그래
- 호들갑 떨거 없어?
- No big deal.
- It's so not a big deal.
- 응, 이따보자
- 그래, 잘가
- I'll see you later. All right, hey.
- Okay, great.
어머나!
Okay..
안됐지만 테이블을
살짝 넘어간것 같은데요
Oh, I'm sorry, I think..
I think that may have missed the table.
- 그래요?
- 네
- Oh, do you?
- Yeah.
- 정말요?
- 그럼요
- Do you?
- Yeah.
- 진짜?
- 그렇다니까요!
- Do you?
- Yeah!
- 저 남자의 저런 모습 좋냐?
- 응
- You really find this attractive on him?
- Oh, yeah.
넌 모니카의 저런 모습에
매력을 못 느끼니?
Are you telling me you're not even
a little turned on by Monica right now?
결혼하고 처음으로
내가 더 매력적인 쪽 같은걸
This is the first time in our marriage that
I've felt like the more attractive one.
좋아! 마이크, 실력 보여줘요
All right, come on, Mike.
You can beat her.
파마머리 납작하게 만들어요
Knock that dog off her head.
- 이런!
- 난 이 남자랑 잤대요!
- Damn it!
- I sleep with him!
- 게임 포인트!
- 잘난척 그만 하시죠
- Game point.
- Don't get too cocky.
아까는 내가 이겼잖아요
Remember, I won the last one.
참, 여자한테 지면
기분이 어때요?
Oh, by the way,
how did that feel, losing to a girl?
본인이 여자인지
거울보고 판단해요
You should look in the mirror
before you call yourself that.
- 안돼, 이럴수가!
- 이리하여 이몸이 이겼습니다
- No! No! No!
- And that's how it's done.
그러면
Okey-dokey.
둘다 한게임씩 이겼네요
1년쯤 흐른것 같긴 하지만
You've each won a game, and I've lost
what's felt like a year of my life.
승자들, 방으로 갈까요?
Everybody goes home a winner.
- 삼세판?
- 그거 좋죠
- Best of three?
- That's what I'm thinking.
투명인간이 되면 무엇을
맞서 싸울까? 범죄 아니면 악?
Should I use my invisibility
to fight crime or for evil?
- 서브 넣어요, 한심 씨!
- "서브 넣어요, 한심 씨!"
- Serve the ball, chump.
- "Serve the ball, chump."
좀더 심한 말을
배워야겠어요
Okay, better comebacks, Mike.
Better comebacks.
앗싸!
I got it!
걱정마, 난 괜찮아!
I'm fine, by the way!
아디론댁 산에 별장이 있으니
I'm just saying,
I have a cabin in the Adirondacks.
도시가 싫을때 한번 들러요
If you ever want to get away
from the city, well, that'd be..
정말 환상적일 거예요
just nifty.
그런데..
제가 할일이 많아서요
Well, I've kind of got a lot
on my plate right now.
낯선 사람과 산에서
주말을 보내는 것도 좋지만요
Not that I wouldn't love a weekend
in the country with a strange man.
- 자비스?
- 왔어?
- Jarvis?
- Oh, you're back.
- 집사람 낸시예요
- 예? 말도 안돼요
- This is my wife, Nancy.
- Well, get out!
- 잠깐 얘기좀 할까요?
- 네, 물론이죠
- Ross? Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Yes, please.
저남자 아직도
날 쳐다보고 있나요?
Is he still looking at me?
네
Yes.
- 지금도요?
- 네
- Still?
- Yes.
저남자 부인은
나를 쳐다보고 있군요
And his wife's kind of looking at me.
어쩐 일로?
So, what's going on?
조이랑 헤어졌어요
Well, Joey and I broke up.
- 세상에, 왜요?
- 좋은 사람이지만
- Oh, my God. What happened?
- Joey is a great guy..
우린 너무 달라요
but we're just..
We're so different.
강연때 직립원인에
웃어대지를 않나
I mean, like, during your speech,
he kept laughing at "Homo erectus."
그녀석인줄 알았어!
I knew that was him!
이게 최선의 선택이라 생각했죠
Anyway, I just..
I think it's for the best.
- 괜찮아요?
- 네
- Hey. Hey, you okay?
- I guess.
그리고..
There was..
조이랑 끝낸 이유가
또 한가지 있었어요
There was another reason that I thought
it was time to end it with Joey.
딴 사람에게 마음이 간걸
알게 됐거든요
I started to realize that I was
having feelings for someone else.
겔러 박사, 기조연설자에게
Okay, Geller.
Last day of the conference.
뭘하는지 알고 있겠지?
You know what happens
to the keynote speaker.
클라릭 교수님
지금 얘기 중이거든요
Professor Klarik, we're in the middle
of a conversation here.
- 풀장엔 나중에 던지시죠
- 둘다 넣는것도 괜찮겠네
- Can't you throw him in the pool later?
- Or we could throw you both in now.
잠깐!
나이에 맞게 행동하시죠
Okay, gentlemen, please.
Aren't we a little old for this?
우린 과학자라고요
지성인이며
I mean, we're scientists, all right?
We're academics..
또 중요한건..
나 잡아봐라!
and most importantly,
you will have to catch us first.
뛰어요!
Go! Go! Go!
41대 41
또 동점이군요
Okay, so it's tied again,
41 to 41.
제발, 그만좀 합시다
- Okay, look, enough is enough.
- No.
- 2점만 나면 우리가 이겨
- 한시간 전부터 그랬잖아
- I just have two more points to beat him.
- Monica, that was also true an hour ago!
자기 꼴좀 봐
I mean, please, look at you.
손엔 물집, 다리엔 힘 빠지고
머리는 말로 형용할 수도 없어
Your hand is blistered, you can
barely stand, your hair is inexplicable!
피비, 좀 도와줘
마이크한테 얘기좀 해봐
Phoebe, talk to Mike. Help me out.
마이크, 이게임을 이기면
Mike, you win this, you will get the best sex
you've ever had in your whole life.
당신 인생의 가장 환상적인
밤을 만들어 줄게요
범죄를 맞서 싸워야겠다
I say to fight crime.
우린 못본거야!
You didn't see us!
모니카?
Monica?
마이크만큼 잘하는지 알았고
You've already proven
you're just as good as he is.
저녁 예약도 날렸으니까
올라가서
We missed our dinner reservations,
so let's just go upstairs..
룸서비스 시키고
샤워하고 자기 머리나 밀자!
order room service, take a shower
and shave your head!
물러설수 없어
4시간이나 했는데
I can't just walk away.
I've put in four hours.
- 그치만..
- 모르고 결혼했어?
You knew this about me
when you married me.
아플때나 건강할 때나
지켜주겠다고 맹세했잖아
You agreed to take me in sickness
and in health.
이게 내 지병이야!
Well, this is my sickness!
- 심하게 깔끔 떠는건?
- 문화인이란 뜻이지!
- What about the obsessive cleaning?
- That's just good sense.
- 괜찮아?
- 됐어, 괜찮아
- You okay?
- No, honey, I'm okay.
할수있어, 이거
손 떨리는거 아냐, 절대아냐
Shake it off. Oh, no shaking.
No shaking. No shaking.
이런, 게임 못하겠어
Oh, my God. I can't play.
- 기권이에요?
- 마이크가 이겼네?
- So you forfeit?
- Mike wins?
말도 안돼
내가 지다니!
I can't believe it. I lost.
- 그렇지 않아
- 뭐라고?
- No, you didn't.
- What?
- 내가 대신 싸울게
- 그건 안되지
- Because I'm gonna play for you.
- You can't do that.
괜찮아요
누구든 때려눕혀 드리죠
It's okay.
I don't care which of them I beat.
그 탁구채 방에서도
쓸모 있겠어요
Okay, we're taking
that paddle home, mister.
- 이럴거 없어
- 할래
- Honey, you don't have to do this.
- Yes, I do.
승리에 집착하는 이유는 몰라도
I may not understand why
you have to win so badly..
자기한테 중요하면
내게도 중요해
but if it's important to you,
it's important to me.
사랑하니까
Because I love you.
그치만..
자긴 형편없잖아
But you suck.
용기줘서 고마워
You're welcome, sweetheart.
단판에 결판짓죠
All right, let's get this over with.
Sudden death.
- 1점내면 이기는 걸로!
- 좋아요
- Whoever wins this point, wins.
- Okay.
- 세상에, 잘하네!
- 포르노보다 더 재밌다
- Oh, my God. You're good.
- It's like watching porn.
이리하여 이몸이
이겼습니다
And that's how it's done.
자기, 진짜 멋있어!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
That was so amazing.
언제 이렇게..
Well, when did you..?
잠깐, 잊은게 있다
이겼지롱!
Hold on, I almost forgot. Loser.
- 왜 못한다고 했어
- 그런말 한적없어, 잘한다는걸
- When did you stop sucking?
- I never sucked. I just didn't want you..
- 숨긴것 뿐이야
- 왜?
- to know how good I was.
- Why?
- 몰라!
- 잘됐다!
- I don't know.
- Well, this is so great.
- 혼합복식도 할수 있겠네
- 이래서야!
- Now we can enter doubles tournaments.
- That's why.
아직도 우릴 찾아요?
- They still looking for us?
- Yeah.
바텐더 말이 두팀으로 나눠
수색하고 있대요
The bartender said they split up
into two search parties.
초식동물팀과 육식동물팀!
The herbivores and the carnivores.
고생물학자들은 노는것도
멋지지 못하군요
You know, we, as a group,
are not the coolest.
조심해요
Oh, look out.
- 우릴 못본거 같아요
- 그런것 같네요
- I don't think they saw us.
- I don't think they did.
연구자들 치곤 관찰력이 꽝이네요
You know, for a bunch of researchers,
they sure don't look very carefully.
아까 하려던 말인데..
So I started to tell you something earlier.
조이랑 헤어져야겠다고 생각한
There was another reason that I realized
it was time to end it with Joey.
또 다른 이유는..
I kind of realized I was starting
to have feelings..
다른사람을 좋아해서예요
for someone else.
누군지 물어봐도 돼요?
And can I ask who?
아시잖아요
I think you know.
알긴 하지만 옛날부터
이런쪽에 실수가 많았거든요
I think I know too, but I've been really
wrong about this stuff in the past, so..
- 안되겠어요
- 알았어요
- I'm sorry, we can't.
- All right. All right.
절친한 친구의 옛 애인과
I mean, you just went out
with my best friend, you know?
이럴순 없어요
I just think it would be a really,
really bad idea.
아닐지도 모르고
Or not. I mean..
왜?
What?